Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
THE YEAR IS 2015 A.D.
THIRD ANGEL
SACHIEL ATTACKS
ORDINARY WEAPONS PROVE
INEFFECTIVE AGAINST THE ANGEL
THE OPERATION IS ABANDONED
BY THE MILITARY
TRANSFERS ALL COMMAND TO
SPECIAL DUTY ORGANIZATION "NERV"
LATE THAT NIGHT,
THE ANGEL ARRIVES DIRECTLY
ABOVE NERV HEADQUARTERS
SEIZED THAT DAY WAS
THIRD CHILD
THE THIRD QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
SHINJI IKARI
ACCEPTS PILOTING DUTY
EVANGELION UNIT 01
FIRST LAUNCH
NERV EXPERIENCES ITS FIRST ACTUAL BATTLE
FIRST DIRECTLY-OVERHEAD ENCOUNTER
EVA UNIT 01, CRANIAL AREA DAMAGED,
RENDERED INOPERABLE
COMPLETE SILENCE
THEN,
LOSS OF CONTROL
"New Tokyo-3 Urban Combat"
Interim Report
Person in Charge
Chief of Operations Captain Misato Katsuragi
Although, as a result, the damage
we incurred was extensive,
the fact is that, against an unknown target,
AND WITH THE THIRD ANGEL AND UNIT 01
a boy with zero experience went out on
his first battle and soundly defeated it.
THE CONFIRMATION OF AN AT FIELD
Shinji Ikari's achievement is
deserving of special notice.
UNIT 01 ERODES TARGET'S AT FIELD
However, for the Department of Operations,
it further highlighted areas of concern
and turned into a bitter battle, the execution
of which left much to be desired.
ANGEL DESTROYED
COUNTERATTACK FACILITIES PARTIALLY DAMAGED
EVA UNIT-01 MODERATELY DAMAGED
EXISTENCE OF VICTIMS OF THIS INCIDENT
NEVER PUBLICIZED
My kid sister's only in the second grade.
Excerpt from Toji Suzuhara's essay
She got hurt in that mess the other day.
And hurt from our side goin' crazy,
not the enemy!
I can't believe how stupid that was.
It's unforgivable!
I'd like to show the adult who made that robot
my sister's sufferin' and my anger!
FOURTH ANGEL
SHAMSHEL ATTACKS
AT THE TIME, GROUND-TO-AIR INTERCEPT SYSTEM
OPERATING AT 48.2%
NEW TOKYO-3
96.8% SWITCHED TO BATTLE CONFIGURATION
I had evacuation drills at school and stuff
all the time with my friends,
Hikari Horiki's note (partial)
So by then it wasn't a big deal
or anything to worry about.
The guys were all acting up
like they were on a field trip,
And none of the girls were afraid either.
ANGEL ARRIVES IN NEW TOKYO-3 AIRSPACE
SECOND DIRECTLY-OVERHEAD ENCOUNTER
SUFFERS ACCIDENT, DISCONNECTED FROM
EXTERNAL POWER SOURCE, HOWEVER...
ANGEL DESTROYED
NERV OBTAINS ANGEL SAMPLE
STILL IN ORIGINAL SHAPE
HOWEVER, A FINAL REPORT ON THE
ANALYSIS RESULTS HAS YET TO BE FILED
FIFTH ANGEL
RAMIEL ATTACKS
AGAINST THIS IMPREGNABLE TARGET,
CAPTAIN KATSURAGI PROPOSES
OPERATION YASHIMA, WHICH IS APPROVED
FIRST CHILD
FIRST QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
DESIGNATED PILOT OF EVA UNIT 00
REI AYANAMI
LAUNCHES FOR THE FIRST TIME IN EVA
UNIT 00 RELEASED FROM CRYOGENIC FREEZE
LATE THAT NIGHT, A PART OF THE ANGEL
INVADES THE GEO-FRONT
NERV DECISIVELY EXECUTES
OPERATION YASHIMA
Ikari didn't tell me anything, but...
Excerpt from Kensuke Aida's personal materials
I think Unit 00 bravely interposed herself
to protect Unit 01
from the enemy's particle beam attack.
No, I'm certain of it.
There's just one reason for that,
and that's Ayanami.
Because she seems to hold little respect
for her own existence.
OPERATION YASHIMA EXECUTED
SUCCESSFULLY
I think it's not quite pessimism, but
she already has something about her.
EVA UNIT 00 HEAVILY DAMAGED
HOWEVER, PILOT RETURNS SAFELY
I find it hard to believe that she's
the same age as we are.
SIXTH ANGEL
ENCOUNTER WITH GAGHIEL
This incident deviated slightly from our script.
Nevertheless, the result was within
the projected parameters.
We can make the necessary adjustments.
SECOND CHILD
SECOND QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
DESIGNATED PILOT OF EVA UNIT 02
ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
FIRST LAUNCH ABOARD EVA UNIT 02
CLOSE QUARTERS COMBAT AT SEA
AND
FIRST UNDERWATER BATTLE
IN AN ENGAGEMENT OFF THE SHORE OF OLD LTOH
ANGEL DESTROYED
The UN Navy lost a third of its
entire fleet in this encounter.
Those ships belonged to your country.
In reality, it's a trivial loss.
Indeed, it's quite fortunate that
the damage was so minor.
SEVENTH ANGEL
ISRAFEL ATTACKS
FIRST ANGEL TO USE DIVIDING
AND MERGING ABILITIES
HOWEVER, WITH THE HEAVY SIMULTANEOUS
2-POINT ATTACK BY EVA UNIT 01 AND UNIT 02
ANGEL DESTROYED
EIGHTH ANGEL
SANDALPHON DISCOVERED
WITHIN MT. ASAMA CRATER
NERV ISSUES ORDER A-17
PRIORITIZED ABOVE ALL ELSE, THE FIRST
CAPTURE OPERATION IS DEPLOYED
CONFINED BRIEFLY IN THE ELECTROMAGNETIC
OPTICAL WAVE ENCLOSURE,
BUT...
THE ELECTROMAGNETIC MEMBRANE IS TORN TO
SHREDS AND THE OPERATION IS INTERRUPTED
OPERATION OBJECTIVE IS IMMEDIATELY
CHANGED TO DESTROYING THE ANGEL
EVA UNIT 02 EXECUTES OPERATION
ANGEL DESTROYED
EVA UNIT-00 RESTORED FROM DAMAGE
AND MODIFICATION WORK COMPLETE
BACK ON DUTY
NINTH ANGEL
MATARAEL ATTACKS
THE FIRST OPERATION WITH ALL THREE EVAS
DEPLOYED AT THE SAME TIME
ANGEL DESTROYED
TENTH ANGEL
SAHAQUIEL ATTACKS
AGAINST THE TARGET FLYING IN
FROM THE STRATOSPHERE
THROUGH DIRECT INTERCEPTION BY THE 3 EVAS
ANGEL DESTROYED
ELEVENTH ANGEL
FACTS CONCERNING THE ATTACK
ARE CURRENTLY UNCONFIRMED
WILD RUMOR OF A DIRECT INVASION
OF NERV HEADQUARTERS
This is no good.
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY COMMITTEE
SPECIAL MEETING CONVENED
It's happening too early.
Indeed!
An Angel invading Nerv HQ
was outside of our schedule.
And worse, to think that you let it
intrude into Central Dogma.
If contact had occurred then,
our entire project could have ended in disaster.
The report to this committee was in error.
No Angel invasion took place.
Ikari, are you then saying the Eleventh Angel's
intrusion did not occur?
Yes.
Speak with caution, Ikari.
Making false statements to this conference
is punishable by death.
You are free to examine the Magi's recorders.
There is no evidence of any such incident.
This is absurd. Hiding the truth is your specialty.
The time schedule is advancing as described
in the Dead Sea Scrolls.
Fine then.
We'll leave aside the matter of crimes
or responsibility on your part.
But there is no need for you
to create a new script.
I realize that.
Everything is proceeding
according to Seele's script.
CHAPTER FOURTEEN
SEELE, THRONE OF SOULS
Mountain...
Heavy mountains.
Things that change over time.
Sky...
Blue sky.
What your eyes can't see.
What your eyes can see.
Sun...
A unique object.
Water...
Something comforting.
Commander Ikari?
Flowers...
So many of the same.
And so many unneeded.
Sky...
Red, red sky.
The color red.
I hate the color red.
Water flowing.
Blood...
The smell of blood.
A woman who never bleeds.
Man made from red soil.
Man made from man and woman.
City... A human creation.
Eva... A human creation.
What is a human? A creation of God?
Is man a human creation?
The things I possess are life and soul.
I am a vessel for a soul.
Entry plug, the throne for a soul.
Who is this? This is me.
Who am I? What am I? What am I?
What am I? What am I?
I am myself.
This object is me.
The form that shapes me.
This is the me that can be seen,
yet I feel as though I am not myself.
Very strange.
I feel as if my body is melting.
I can no longer see myself.
My shape is fading.
I feel the presence of someone who is not me.
Is someone there, beyond this?
Ikari?
I know this person. Major Katsuragi.
Doctor Akagi.
Everyone.
Classmates.
The pilot of Unit 02.
Commander Ikari?
Who are you?
So, Rei, how does it feel to be piloting
Unit 01 for the first time?
It smells like Ikari.
FIRST UNIT INTERCHANGEABILITY TEST
SUBJECT REI AYANAMI
Her synch rate is almost the same
as with Unit 00.
Unit 00 and 01's personal data patterns
are very similar too, after all.
That's exactly what makes this
synchronization possible.
Error is plus or minus 0.03.
Harmonics are normal.
No interchangeability problems detected
between Rei and Unit 01.
Okay, the test is finished.
Rei, you can get out now.
Yes, Ma'am.
87TH UNIT LINK-UP TEST
SUBJECT ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
Data bank for Unit 02 complete.
Harmonics are all normal.
Pilot status normal.
Of course!
FIRST UNIT INTERCHANGEABILITY TEST
SUBJECT SHINJI IKARI
Entry plug insertion complete.
What about Unit 00's personal data?
Already reconfigured. Currently reconfirming.
Subject status?
He appears a bit nervous, but no problems
in his nerve patterns.
This is his first time in Unit 00.
It's another Eva, so it's only natural.
He's so stupid. He should just take it easy
and not worry about those things.
Shinji's just not that kind of person.
I know, that's why he's stupid.
Speaking of which, don't I need to be involved
in their interchangeability test?
You don't want to pilot an Eva
besides Unit 02 anyway, do you?
Well, you've got that right.
Eva Unit 02 definitely
wouldn't be interchangeable.
Entry has commenced.
LCL electrolyzed.
Initiating first connection.
Shinji, how do you feel in Unit 00's entry plug?
It feels kind of odd.
A sense of incongruity?
No, it's just that...
It smells like Ayanami.
What does he mean, smell? Is he a pervert?
Data received. Reconfirming. Pattern green.
Main power supply connection complete.
All restraints are normal.
Roger.
Now let's shift to the second stage
of the interchangeability tests.
Unit 00 will enter into second contact.
How is it?
As I thought, the synch rate is lower
than that of Unit 01.
Harmonics are all normal.
But these are still good readings.
This means we can implement that plan.
The dummy system, you mean?
I know you support it, but I'm not so...
I understand why you wouldn't approve,
but we always need to be prepared
so that mankind can survive.
I highly respect you, Ma'am,
and I will do my duty,
but I am not convinced about this project.
It's tough having a fastidious nature,
as far as living among people goes.
You'll understand that when
you feel that you've been sullied.
Initiating third connection.
Self psycho-graph is stable.
Hey, Shin, how do you like mommy's breast?
Or is it more like inside her womb?
Asuka, it'll introduce data noise. Don't interfere.
Okay, okay.
What's with them? They're all so quick
to mollycoddle Shinji.
Initiate A-10 nerve connection.
Harmonics level, plus twenty.
What is this?
Something's trying to get directly into my brain.
Ayanami?
Rei Ayanami?
This impression is Rei Ayanami, isn't it?
Ayanami?
Isn't it her?
What's going on?
We've got a problem occurring
in the pilot's nerve pulse.
Pulse reversing!
Mental contamination is taking place.
Impossible! That can't happen
at this plug depth.
It's not from the plug.
The intrusion's coming from the Eva.
Unit 00 is out of control!
Shut off all circuits! Cut the power supply!
Eva has switched to backup power.
Still operational.
How's Shinji?
The circuit's disconnected.
We can't monitor him!
Unit 00 is rejecting Shinji?
It's no good! The auto eject's not working!
The same thing as before...
Is it going to try to absorb Shinji?
Rei, get back! Rei!
Activation will be terminated in ten...
9...
8...
7...
6...
5...
4...
3...
2...
1...
Zero!
Unit 00 has ceased activation.
Hurry up and rescue the pilot!
Could it be that Unit 00 just tried to kill Rei?
Was this somehow related to
the earlier berserk incident
when Rei was the pilot?
I can't tell you anything right now.
I only know we must reconfigure Unit 00
for Rei's personal data,
and run a new synch test between them
as soon as possible.
As Chief of Operations, I ask that you do so
as soon as possible,
before it impacts our work.
I know, Major Katsuragi.
The person Unit 00 wanted to hit was me.
I'm sure of it.
And now the next contestant
for the World's Most Amazing Exhibition is,
Math Puppy!
Wow, that sounds awesome!
Here we go, math genius puppy,
Kana, from Niigata!
Wan!
He sounds good. Do you understand me?
Oh, right. Now let's ask him.
Wan!
What is 325 minus 324?
That's amazing! He's correct!
I hate it. It's this ceiling again.
Shinji has regained consciousness.
No signs of mental contamination.
He doesn't appear to remember anything.
I see.
Hi! I'm doing fine,
but the world is worrisome due to
terrorism in the Nansa Islands.
Misato and Mr. Kaji won't tell me,
This year long heat creates some crazy
bastards, you know?
And Shinji doesn't even know.
What I can't stand is those suicidal idiots
that involve innocent people!
Just what kind of girl is the First Child?
The Angel invasion that deviated from the plan.
Knight
So the Human Instrumentality Committee is
taking advantage of having learned of it.
Though they're just worthless fools whose job
is to do nothing but complain.
We hold all the trump cards.
There is nothing they can do.
Still, that doesn't mean we should provoke them.
If Seele starts interfering now, it'll be trouble,
in more ways than one.
Everything is going according to our script.
There is no problem.
What about the Unit 00 accident?
That wasn't in my script.
It is no obstacle.
The re-synchronization test for Rei
and Unit 00 was successful.
Ikari is too concerned about Rei.
What is the status of the Adam Project?
Proceeding smoothly. It's not even
two percent behind schedule.
Then, the Lance of Longinus is...
It's going as planned.
Rei is carrying out the operation.
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
With her friends getting married
one after another,
Misato alone begins to get worked up.
Could the reunion between her and Kaji
be her last chance?
Next episode: "Lies and Silence"
LIES AND SILENCE